{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Glycolytic pathway regulation involves", "opta": "allosteric stimulation by ADP", "optb": "allosteric inhibition by ATP", "optc": "feedback, or product, inhibition by ATP", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "During catabolism, only about 40% of the energy available from oxidizing glucose is used to synthesize ATP. Remaining 60%", "opta": "is lost as heat", "optb": "is used to reduce NADP", "optc": "remains in the products of metabolism", "optd": "is stored as fat.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Why does the glycolytic pathway continue in the direction of glucose catabolism?", "opta": "There are essentially three irreversible reactions that act as the driving force for the pathway", "optb": "High levels of ATP  keep the pathway going in a forward direction", "optc": "The enzymes of glycolysis only function in one direction", "optd": "Glycolysis occurs in either direction", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The released energy obtained by oxidation of glucose is stored as", "opta": "a concentration gradient across a membrane", "optb": "ADP", "optc": "ATP", "optd": "NAD+", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A kinase is an enzyme that", "opta": "removes phosphate groups of substrates", "optb": "uses ATP to add a phosphate group to the substrate", "optc": "uses NADH to change the oxidation state of the substrate", "optd": "removes water from a double bond", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For every one molecule of sugar glucose which is oxidized __________ molecule of pyruvic acid are produced.", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "3", "optd": "4", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the glycogen synthase reaction, the precursor to glycogen is", "opta": "glucose-6-P", "optb": "UTP-glucose", "optc": "UDP-glucose", "optd": "glucose-1-P", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The active form of glycogen phosphorylase is phosphorylated, while the dephosphorylation of which active form occurs?", "opta": "Glycogen synthase", "optb": "Glycogen semisynthase", "optc": "Glycogen hydrolase", "optd": "Glycogen dehydrogenase", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The amount of energy received from one ATP is", "opta": "76 kcal", "optb": "7.3 kcal", "optc": "760 kcal", "optd": "1000 kcal", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The enzymes of glycolysis in a eukaryotic cell are located in the", "opta": "intermembrane space", "optb": "plasma membrane", "optc": "cytosol", "optd": "mitochondrial matrix", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When concentration of the reactants is higher than the equilibrium concentration then", "opta": "the gibbs free energy will be positive", "optb": "the gibbs free energy will be negative", "optc": "more products will be formed", "optd": "both (b) and (c)", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not true of glycolysis?", "opta": "ADP is phosphorylated to ATP via substrate level phosphorylation", "optb": "The pathway does not require oxygen", "optc": "The pathway oxidizes two moles of NADH to NAD+ for each mole of glucose that enters", "optd": "The pathway requires two moles of ATP to get started catabo-lizing each mole of glucose", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In glycolysis, ATP is formed by the transfer of a high-energy phosphate from 1,3-bisphosphoglycerate to ADR No such high-energy phosphate donor has ever been isolated in mitochondria because", "opta": "the techniques for isolating the phosphate donor are not refined enough", "optb": "no such phosphate donor exists", "optc": "the high-energy phosphate donor is very short-lived and difficult to isolate", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "ATP is from which general category of molecules?", "opta": "Polysaccharides", "optb": "Proteins", "optc": "Nucleotides", "optd": "Amino acids", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The glycolytic pathway (glucose \u2192 2 pyruvate) is found", "opta": "in all living organisms", "optb": "primarily in animals excluding particles", "optc": "only in eukaryotes", "optd": "only in yeast", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following could act as an uncoupler of electron transport and ATP synthesis?", "opta": "The Fo base-piece of ATP synthase (without the Fl subunit)", "optb": "Dinitrophenol", "optc": "neither (a) nor (b)", "optd": "Both (a) and (b)", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not a mechanism for altering the flux of metabolites through the rate-determining step of a pathway?", "opta": "Allosteric control of the enzyme activity", "optb": "Diffusional coupling between adjacent active sites", "optc": "Genetic control of the enzyme concentration", "optd": "Covalent modification of the enzyme", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Phosphofructokinase, the major flux-controlling enzyme of glycolysis is allosterically inhibited and activated respectively by", "opta": "ATP and PEP", "optb": "AMP and Pi", "optc": "ATP and ADP", "optd": "Citrate and ATP", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following regulates glycolysis steps?", "opta": "Phosphofructokinase", "optb": "Hexose kinase", "optc": "Pyruvate kinase", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "During glycolysis, the major energy generating step involves", "opta": "pyruvate kinase", "optb": "phosphoglycerate kinase", "optc": "glyceraldehyde-3 -dehydrogenase", "optd": "Phosphofructokinase", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Fructose-2,6-bisphosphate", "opta": "activates fructose-1,6-bisphosphatase", "optb": "activates phosphofructokinase", "optc": "inhibits fructose-1,6-bisphosphatase", "optd": "both (b) and (c)", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Glucose from the breakdown of glycogen is obtained in", "opta": "the liver by phosphorolysis", "optb": "the muscles by phosphorolysis", "optc": "the muscles by hydrolysis", "optd": "both (a) and (b)", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Glycogen has", "opta": "\u03b1-1,4 linkage", "optb": "\u03b1-1,6 linkages", "optc": "\u03b1-1,4 and \u03b1-1,6 linkages", "optd": "\u03b1-1,4 and \u03b2-1,6 linkage", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}